They call themselves "The Goonies." The secret caves. The old lighthouse. The lost map.
The treacherous traps. The hidden adventure. And Sloth… Join the adventure.
The Goonies is a adventure, comedy, family film directed by Richard Donner.
Young teen Mikey Walsh and his friends set off on a quest to find Pirate One-Eyed
Willie's treasure in hopes of saving their homes from demolition.
However, on their quest to find the treasure, they run into a family of recently escaped
criminals, determined to capture the kids and reach the treasure first.
Mikey, played by Sean Astin.
Brand, played by Josh Brolin.
Chunk, played by Jeff Cohen.
Mouth, played by Corey Feldman.
Andy, played by Kerri Green.
Stef, played by Martha Plimpton.
The Goonies is a 1985 American adventure comedy film directed by Richard Donner from
a screenplay by Chris Columbus based on a story by Steven Spielberg.
The film stars Sean Astin, Josh Brolin (in his film debut), Jeff Cohen (in his only feature film), Corey Feldman, Kerri Green (in her film
debut), Martha Plimpton, and Ke Huy Quan with John Matuszak, Robert Davi, Joe Pantoliano, and Anne Ramsey in supporting roles.
In the film, a group of children who live in the "Goon Docks" neighborhood of
Astoria, Oregon attempt to save their homes from foreclosure.
In doing so, they discover an old treasure map which takes them on an adventure to unearth the long-lost fortune of One-Eyed Willy,
a legendary 17th-century pirate, while being pursued by a family of criminals who are after the treasure as well.
The film was produced by Spielberg's Amblin
Entertainment and released by Warner Bros.
theatrically on June 7, 1985, in the United States.
The film grossed $125 million worldwide on a budget of $19 million.
Critics reviewed the film positively and it has since become a cult film.
In 2017, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
On February 14, 2025, a sequel was confirmed to be in the works with Potsy Ponciroli
writing the script along with Steven Spielberg and Chris Columbus producing.
The film explores themes of gang of thieves, treasure
map, oregon, usa, gunfight, pirate.
The tone is lighthearted.